KATHRYN WOHL

Full Stack Software Developer

PROFILE

After several years solving issues and anticipating needs in the hospitality industry, I'm trading one form of creative problem solving for another and embarking on a new career in tech. I couldn't be more excited to challenge myself and use the practical skills I've developed in this new and dynamic field.

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/katie-wohl/
- github.com/kwohl wohl.github.io

PROJECTS

Kitchen Companion

Kitchen Companion is an application to assist a restaurant kitchen with inventory management by creating a grocery list to which all members of the kitchen staff can add items from their mobile devices. Admin users have a range of functionality including managing suppliers and item databases, generating and categorizing orders, and managing user accounts. The app was built using React.js and styled with Semantic UI and CSS, and all data is stored in a JSON database.

• github.com/kwohl/kitchen-companion

Domino

Domino is a full-stack application that allows users to create to-do lists, track their progress, and break tasks in to easy-tomanage steps. The app is built with a React.js front-end and a Django REST API back-end.

- github.com/kwohl/domino
- github.com/kwohl/domino-api

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp

Chattanooga State Community College

AA, Foreign Language - Spanish

Universidad de Extremadura

Spanish Conversation - Study Abroad

University of Tennessee - Chattanooga

Theatre Arts

Theatre Arts

University of Oregon

2010 - 2012

2009 - 2010

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Six-month, intensive software development bootcamp. Tech stack: Python, Django, JavaScript, React.js, SQLite, HTML, CSS

Full Stack Software Developer

- Gained hands on experience working with teams of developers to produce projects using Git and Github
- Created individual and team-based front-end and server-side projects with full CRUD functionality

Group Projects

Nutshell

github.com/nss-day-cohort-38/react-nutshell-pyroclastic-thunder-nerds Nutshell is a dashboard-style application built first using vanilla JavaScript and then using React.js. It allows users to save events, news, and to-do lists, add friends, and create and view

Bangazon LLC github.com/nss-day-cohort-38/bangazon-ecommerce-web-app-eos-terminal Bangazon is an e-commerce application built using a React, is front-end and a Django REST API back-end. I worked on several sections including CRUD functionality for products and managing current and past orders.

SpringHill Suites by Marriott

messages. I was responsible for the events section.

2018 - 2019

Technologies Used: Fosse, MARSHA, SalesPro, Excel, Quore, Guest Request, Text Request Guest Service Manager

 Responded to guest complaints, managed front office operations, managed invoicing, checked payroll, managed hotel inventory

Front Office Supervisor

- Supervised front desk team of 7, managed employee schedules, handled guest complaints, ensured positive guest experiences
- Ran nightly audit and maintained daily numbers spreadsheets

Sales & Events Coordinator

 Coordinated events and meetings for four meeting spaces ranging from 12 to 100 in capacity, managed catering accounts, responded to sales leads, negotiated group and event rates

Front Desk Representative

2014 - 2017

• Checked guests in and out, processed billing, responded to guest complaints, catered to guest needs, performed various clerical and administrative duties including answering a multi-line phone and spreadsheet maintenance

Freelance

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Editor

 Collaborated on video ideas, created and edited scripts, newsletters, updates, and other written content

Content/Community Manager

- · Assisted in sponsorship negotiation, hired and supervised artists, strategized methods of
- Worked with a team of community managers to moderate, engage with, and grow a community of followers on Twitch and YouTube
- Brainstormed and produced content for Twitch and YouTube

Holiday Inn Express

2012 - 2014

Technologies Used: Opera

Sales Associate & Front Desk Represesentative

- Managed and maintained relations between the hotel and various corporate accounts
- Negotiated rates and secured new business including both event and business travelers
- Handled customer service related issues and worked to ensure that every guest had a positive experience
- Acted as the hotel's Green Engage representative, which involved monitoring utilities and adjusting policies to become more environmentally friendly and to save money.
- Performed various clerical and administrative duties including answering a multi line phone, filing, spreadsheet maintenance, and editing